<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Michele Buonanduci</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmon, forests, and fire working group</title>
      <link>/project/snapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/snapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://snappartnership.net/teams/salmon-forests-and-fire/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Science for Nature and People Partnership (SNAPP)&lt;/a&gt;
 working group aims to improve the health and resilience of salmonids, forests, and the human communities that rely on them in wildfire-prone areas. Efforts to restore dwindling salmonid populations and efforts to increase forest resilience to wildfire have largely been managed by separate and uncoordinated policies and agencies. An integrated approach is urgently needed to address salmonid recovery and wildfire resilience in the face of climate change and corresponding increases in wildfire activity. This SNAPP working group brings together scientists and managers from multiple disciplines (including geomorphology, ecology, and social science) and multiple sectors (tribal, federal, academic, and nongovernmental conservation institutions) to develop resources that will share, support, and increase awareness about the need for more integrated approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Western Fire &amp; Forest Resilience Collaborative</title>
      <link>/project/wffrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wffrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.westernfireforest.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Western Fire and Forest Resilience Collaborative (WFFRC)&lt;/a&gt;
 is a research program designed to accelerate scientific discoveries that will enhance forest resilience and wildfire decision making. WFFRC partners with fire management and policy experts to understand, catalyze, and deliver the science they need. We are co-creating and implementing a research program that will ensure that forest stewards have the best available science to inform long-term planning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
