<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Michele Buonanduci</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salmon, forests, and fire working group</title>
      <link>/project/snapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/snapp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://snappartnership.net/teams/salmon-forests-and-fire/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Science for Nature and People Partnership (SNAPP)&lt;/a&gt;
 working group aims to improve the health and resilience of salmonids, forests, and the human communities that rely on them in wildfire-prone areas. The working group will combine research on forest management for wildfire resilience with salmonid restoration and apply this to local conservation efforts. The group will create a salmonid-fire-vegetation database to quantify fish-fire relationships, identify factors that support fish resilience to fire, and develop tools for integrating wildfire management with salmonid recovery. The group will also work to identify communities where managers can be engaged to adapt and apply this integrated framework to meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Western Fire &amp; Forest Resilience Collaborative</title>
      <link>/project/wffrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wffrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.westernfireforest.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Western Fire and Forest Resilience Collaborative (WFFRC)&lt;/a&gt;
 is a research program designed to accelerate scientific discoveries that will enhance forest resilience and wildfire decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forest restoration and salmon resilience</title>
      <link>/project/ellsworth-salmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ellsworth-salmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As climate change alters freshwater, estuarine, and marine habitats, Pacific salmon need increasing levels of conservation action to maintain population health. In the Pacific Northwest, USA, coastal forests and estuarine ecosystems have experienced extensive anthropogenic change since the early 20th century, and significant investments in restoration and conservation are currently underway. Restoration is increasingly implemented within the broad-scale context of changing ocean conditions, but we lack an understanding of the relative extent to which land-based actions can contribute to the resilience of salmon populations under climate change. We addressed this challenge using an integrated population model of chum salmon (&lt;em&gt;Oncorhynchus keta&lt;/em&gt;) in the Willapa basin (southwest Washington, USA). We first conducted a retrospective analysis, evaluating how chum population dynamics have varied with watershed-scale forest management, estuarine invasive species control efforts, and changing ocean conditions from 1984 to 2022. Forest management and estuarine restoration both had measurable effects on population dynamics, as did nearshore ocean conditions. Using this model, we projected chum population dynamics under a range of future climate and forest management scenarios. Our results suggest the viability of our focal populations may decline with ocean warming, but that maintaining and promoting watershed-scale forest structural complexity can decrease the risk of population collapse compared to a scenario in which forests are intensively harvested. Overall, our findings illustrate the capacity for multiple conservation actions to contribute to salmon population health and suggest that watershed-scale forest management has the potential to bolster the persistence of salmon populations under climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
