<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Michele Buonanduci</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn severity spatial scaling</title>
      <link>/project/burn-severity-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/burn-severity-scaling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;West of the Cascade Divide in Washington and northern Oregon (&amp;ldquo;western Cascadia&amp;rdquo;), moist coniferous forests are characterized by infrequent, typically high-severity stand-replacing fire with multi-century fire return intervals and fire events as large as one million hectares in size. As climate warms, the largest future increases in area burned may occur in ecosystems such as western Cascadia, where climate tends to be the limiting factor. To anticipate the ecological impacts of future increases in area burned in western Cascadia, understanding not only the relative likelihood of small/moderate versus very-large fires, but also the range of potential high-severity patch structure within those respective fire sizes, will be critical. This project will examine the spatial patterns of contemporary fires (1984-2020) that have occurred across the Northwest US, developing an &lt;em&gt;atlas&lt;/em&gt; of spatial scaling laws that relate high-severity patch structure to overall fire size. We will then evaluate whether and where contemporary fires in western Cascadia fall within this atlas of spatial scaling laws. The objectives of this research are to increase our understanding of the natural range of variation in wildfire patch structure across western Cascadia, and also to help managers better prepare for wildfire in this region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biotic disturbance hotspots</title>
      <link>/project/hot-spots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/hot-spots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interactions among disturbance agents are increasingly important to consider as climate warms and disturbance activity changes. Preliminary research has suggested that the occurrence of biotic disturbance &lt;em&gt;hotspots&lt;/em&gt; (i.e., areas where disturbances from two or more biotic agents are co-occurring in space and time) may be increasing in the western United States in recent years. An increase in biotic disturbance hotspots would have important implications for the resilience of forests in the face of climate change, particularly if disturbance agents have compound or synergistic effects. However, an exploration of the broad-scale factors associated with these hotspots (e.g., climate, weather, vegetation structure, topography) has not been conducted to date. This project will build on research that is already underway by my advisor (Dr. Brian J. Harvey) and his collaborators, who are evaluating whether increases in area of biotic disturbance hotspots are greater than expected from random chance during a period of increasing overall biotic disturbances.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compensatory responses following bark beetle outbreak</title>
      <link>/project/fef-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fef-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bark beetle outbreaks structure forests not only directly via mortality of overstory trees but also indirectly by releasing the growth of understory trees as resource availability (i.e., light, water, and nutrient availability) increases for survivors. This growth release is a &lt;em&gt;compensatory response&lt;/em&gt; of trees adapted to periodic bark beetle outbreaks, preserving ecosystem function. The growth release of trees surviving bark beetle outbreaks has been well documented at the stand scale and has frequently been used to detect the occurrence of past outbreaks. However, the impact of within-stand spatial configuration (e.g., overstory mortality, live tree composition) on surviving tree growth release is less well understood. This project utilizes a spatially explicit long-term monitoring dataset of over 9,000 individually measured and mapped trees in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.usda.gov/rmrs/experimental-forests-and-ranges/fraser-experimental-forest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fraser Experimental Forest&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host tree mortality from bark beetle outbreak</title>
      <link>/project/fef-pico-mpb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/fef-pico-mpb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While drivers of bark beetle outbreaks have been studied extensively at spatial scales ranging from stands to continents, within-stand processes governing individual tree mortality in an outbreak are less well understood. Here we used a spatially explicit long-term monitoring dataset of over 9,000 individually measured and mapped trees in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fs.usda.gov/rmrs/experimental-forests-and-ranges/fraser-experimental-forest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fraser Experimental Forest&lt;/a&gt;
 (CO, USA) to explore interactions among fine scale drivers of beetle-caused tree mortality. Using a Bayesian spatial modeling approach, we evaluated how tree scale and tree neighborhood scale characteristics interact with tree size to mediate host tree susceptibility to mountain pine beetle outbreak in the Southern Rocky Mountains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed this project as part of my Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis, entitled &amp;ldquo;Modeling individual lodgepole pine mortality from mountain pine beetle outbreak in a spatially explicit framework&amp;rdquo;, which I defended in November 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
